In insurance, there is no diagnosis
provision. Now, when you lie, the lie has
no wings. You did
n't give us a chance to take the risk, so why should we pay that claim? Or what, at
least do one thing.
Come and get treatment after 6 months. We propose after 6 months. We postpone
and defer your
sugar level from 120. How much do you want to see?
We will reimburse you. We will reload you. We do
n't reload you. Once you have applied the loading, it is
applied. The
declaration rate in the life insurance industry is
only 1%.
[Music]
Friends, I have a big doubt in my mind,
and many people have this doubt.
If I want to take an insurance policy
and I have diabetes, then
I do
n't declare in the insurance policy form that I have
diabetes. The reason for this is that I
feel that if the insurance company
agrees to give me the policy, it might
reject my policy application form.
This is a doubt in my mind as well, and many
people have this doubt, and many
people even implement it, that is, the
form  But let's not write, today we are going to meet once again
Mr. Ganesh Iyer
who is the CEO of Progress Group and
as you all know that he has worked in the
insurance and underwriting department for many years, almost 20-20 years.
Apart from this, Mr. Ganesh
[Music]
and many doctors have also worked under him.
Ganesh ji, I welcome you once again
and as
you heard that this is a doubt, there is a doubt in our mind
and this doubt is in the mind of all the people that
if I take an insurance policy
and I have diabetes, if I
declare this, then my insurance
policy is going to be rejected, so I will
not declare it at all, but this is what you
want to say now, I have
cleared this and declared any element
and will directly decline it from the insurance company,
otherwise, then see, there are many people in sales also
who say this themselves,
not everyone says this, but
even the sales people are afraid, they have this in their mind that
if we write it on the form, then
its policy will be rejected a little heavily.  It will be rejected
again. This is also a
big miscommunication. In fact, sales
think that the underwriting company is sitting there to
stop the business, to reject it
or they do not want to take the risk at all. This is a
big misunderstanding.
Okay, they should understand the fact that I would like to give the
message to all the sales teams in the
insurance industry. Underwriters are there to get the
right business for the company and bring in
premium and profit. So, do
not think that it is their responsibility.
Stopping the business is their concern,
not to stop the business, they just want to write it. But they are there to get the right
business.
I agree with you that
underwriters and insurance companies are there to
get the business. But it is
also true that if I declare
that I have diabetes, then there are some
chances, I am not saying 100%. There are chances that
some premium will be deducted from my policy. These are the chances. So,
I think that if I get the
exclusion list of Help Insurance, if
I write diabetes then  If I get 3 years
exclusion then anyway
in any condition I am going to get 3 years exclusion
after informing so if
I have given this command to my man
that I will not declare at all
and even if a claim comes then I will
not claim for 3 years, after three years the
company is not going to know at all
what will you say on this,
first of all you have predicted that the company will
not know at all, how will they know after 3 years, they can
know only after 10 years,
how will that happen, in our Klein series
you knew that after so many years we get to know what happened in the past, what
information is available, okay so if
you have diabetes for the last 10 years or
since childhood, you can also go for insurance claim,
go to health or life, you say that
I have diabetes only for 6 months, your documentation,
your diagnosis happened 3 years ago, 10 years ago, and at the end
moment
okay your policy will be issued, but the
reason for which you took the policy  The idea was that I should be able to get a claim and
help my family live a peaceful life, if you do
n't get that benefit then what is the benefit of yours, okay
and you got tagged that you have done non
disclosure, it is not giving your
example, you said that I will be subject to exclusion
or the rate will increase or decline at that
rate, you did not do it, I have to
claim after 3 years, oh brother, you had to
claim after 3 years only, take the exclusion,
what difference does it make, at least the company is
aware that you have a problem, they said
that now you cannot claim this for three years, you
cannot claim this particular element which is diabetes,
when you lie then there is no justification for the lie,
then you said here that you cannot say it here, so it is
better that you take exclusion and if
something happens for 3 years, then
bear the small expenditure yourself in health insurance, the
company does not have any
heart problem for 3 years, okay let's do the
loading, a
little premium of Rs. 100  In return you had to pay Rs 125, you
agreed but again you get
peace in this it is not costly of I will not open the
truth, thank you very much, we examined you as per
your health,
you have to pay this premium, it is wrong,
now even when you go to buy a product, some
things become more costly because
some features are different in it, so your paying
for these features but then you are peaceful, your
purpose is solved,
last thing if I say that your policy is going to be declared, proposed, declined, let's say
specifically life insurance,
okay then I will say brother, insurance and
second priority, first take care of your health, take care of your
life, take care of your family
because the
insurance company will not declare
normal course
diabetes, so come and get the best level possible
treatment, we cannot propose after 6 months, we will do it
later, the
problem is not yours, it is not for today
because you will get one in this, I will
slide DVD, it is very important for people to
understand the difference between a normal clinical
doctor and an insurance doctor  Okay there are
you technical terms which I ignore Okay that's
called diagnosis which you might have heard in general, the
doctor diagnoses this,
in insurance the word is not diagnosis, in the
word it is prognosis,
so explain it in this simple term, if Ranjeet
ji Cook has stomach ache and
goes to the local doctor and says
like this doctor sahib I am having stomach ache, the doctor sahib will
tell you that there is a
problem in such and such place, you take this medicine, you will be
fine in two-three days,
you ask the doctor brother make a warranty
certificate that I will not have this problem for the next 10 years,
when I have a problem, come back
today, what is the reason for this and
how should I do it, so much
diagnosis has been solved, you can go
again, you can go to Tiwara, but
you come once to the insurance company, they
tell you one thing or once
your medical report is done, then it is in the life insurance policy for the next 10-20 years,
your test is
not done again, how will we reload the 4 months, it is
not done once  You have got the
loading charge, it has been levied, we do
n't tell you the second time, we like it
every 2 months, you can get it every two years
and right, that's because the insurance company has
checked your current status and made a
prognosis in between, for the next 10, 20, 30, 40 years,
what is it to me if I can take the insurance and
then why should I pay this
extra premium or brother I
cannot take this risk because your life
condition is so sub standard that
not only diabetes, you can also have this problem because of this because
of your respect help
parameters, now if they have declined you, then
my brother you too will have insurance
problem, you really need to take care
help because the insurance which is protecting you from this problem may not come
today,
maybe it will not come to me for 2 years, 5 years, 10 years, 15 years
or maybe it will not come to me or maybe to any insurer,
but it is more important for you to know the reason for this
and let me tell you that the
declature rate in the life insurance industry is 1%,
sir, rest  Out of 99,
generally everything is considered standard rate,
some people charge loading, it is a myth
that if I have diabetes then I should declare it
with the understanding that if I have diabetes then
I will have to pay a little extra
premium for it, because I have diabetes
I should not suffer because my
risk is higher and the other person
's premium is lower, not only diabetes other
habits, whatever questions you are asked, please please please will
not be known, we are living in a digital world,
your medical records are also getting digitalized,
you know, right now when you go to a diagnostic
center, they will ask you, you don't know, they will
show your entire history from your telephone number, they will give you the report
and now the government is also coming with our
headset and date, this Ayushman Bharat is coming,
so plus digital ID is going to come, so
what will happen with this, your life, everyone's
life is going to become very simple, we will go to an Aadhar
based connection connected world,
so you go to any part of the
country, even if you do not check the report,
your digital report will reach you,
your history will be saved, so it is
beneficial for you, but don't  If you forget that your
document will remain there for
years, then
you cannot say that I can give it by lying, then
you should realize and it is good,
you should be ethical and it is more important in our nation
today, the question is that some developed
nations do not do these things and there without any
fact we are doing it out of fear, maybe because of some brother, if
we tell the truth then I will not say cost of
truth, I will say cost of debt,
substantiated like this, you should be paid which is good for us all, the information
you have given is very
good and very important information too, thank you
very much for this, thank you
sir and I would like to come to my viewers
and I would also like to tell you that
even today there are many people, in fact
educated people, who many times it happens that due to many
things of theirs, they
feel that their insurance may be rejected, they do
not share such information,
whether it is about diabetes or something or any habit, they are
afraid to share it because of the fear that it will impact their
policy.  It is
possible that whether it is the premium
or the policy may get rejected but this
mistake should not be made because the
policy is not rejected every time, the
premium of the policy does not increase every time, exclusions are
not imposed every time and instead of hiding
things by giving wrong information and hiding things, I have to
take a different risk that
tomorrow my claim may also get rejected, so
this is a very important understanding and
with this understanding, if you ever take any insurance policy in future, then
definitely declare your things, today's episode
with Ganesh ji,
what are your thoughts about it, tell us by writing in the comments, if you liked the
video then
like the video and do share this video with all the people you know
who are interested in insurance news and
insurance matters,
thank you very much
[Music]
[Praise]
Subscribe to Bitv channel, press the bell icon
[Music]